THE LEGEND - John Wayne is 'Chisum'
Chisum is a western film directed by Andrew V. McLaglen.
Cattle baron John Chisum joins forces with Billy the Kid and Pat Garrett to fight
the Lincoln County Land War in the New Mexico Territory of 1878.
John Chisum, played by John Wayne.
Lawrence Murphy, played by Forrest Tucker.
Dan Nodeen, played by Christopher George.
James Pepper, played by Ben Johnson.
Pat Garrett, played by Glenn Corbett.
Alex McSween, played by Andrew Prine.
Chisum is a 1970 American Western film directed by Andrew V.
McLaglen, starring John Wayne in the title role, and
adapted for the screen by Andrew J.
Fenady from his short story "Chisum and the Lincoln County War".
The supporting cast features Forrest Tucker, Christopher George, Ben Johnson, Glenn Corbett, Andrew Prine, Bruce Cabot, Patric Knowles, Richard Jaeckel, Lynda Day, Pedro
Armendáriz Jr., John Agar, John Mitchum, Ray Teal, Christopher Mitchum, and Hank Worden, with Geoffrey Deuel and Pamela McMyler receiving "introducing" credits.
The picture was filmed in Panavision and Technicolor.
Chisum is based on the Lincoln County War of 1878, and although it changed a number of details, many of the historical figures in the film (such as Chisum,
Tunstall, McSween, Murphy, Brady, Evans, Garrett, and Billy the Kid) were in the New Mexico Territory at the time and did play a part in the conflict.
The film explores themes of gunslinger, monopoly,
moral conflict, cattle drive, gun battle.